Guide to the James A. Gross Collections 1916-1995
Gross, James A., Collections
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
James A. Gross Collections, 1916-1995
/4349
Gross, James A.; National Labor Relations Board; Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives
102 linear ft.
Files, records (documents), papers (documents), audiovisual materials, photographs.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library
Audio recordings of Prof. Jim Gross's interviews used when he was doing research on the NLRB Audio of James Gross's interviews with Melvin Welles, D. Pollitt, Thomas Miller, Jr., Ed Miller and Frank McCulloch. Prof. James Gross's collection of miscellaneous NLRB photographs
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor Gross teaches Labor Law, Labor Arbitration, and a course entitled Values, Rights and Justice in Economics, Law, and Industrial Relations. He received his B.S. from LaSalle College, M.A. from Temple University, and Ph.D. from University of Wisconsin.
Professor Gross is a member of National Academy of Arbitrators and on the labor arbitration panels of the American Arbitration Association, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service and New York State Public Employment Relations Board, as well as being a panelist named in several contracts.[www.ilr.cornell.edu/directory/jag28/biography.htm]
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
NLRB 1935-2010
The National Labor Relations Board is proud of its 75-year history of enforcing the National Labor Relations Act, the primary law governing relations between employers and employees in the private sector. On July 5, 1935, President Franklin Roosevelt signed the Act into law, stating that the law sought to achieve "common justice and economic advance." Starting in the Great Depression and continuing through World War II and the economic growth and challenges that followed, the NLRB has worked to guarantee the rights of employees to bargain collectively, if they choose to do so.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Audio of James Gross's interviews with Melvin Welles, D. Pollitt, Thomas Miller, Jr., Ed Miller and Frank McCulloch.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Gross, James A.,1933-; McCulloch, Frank; Miller, Thomas; Miller, Ed; Welles, Melvin; National Labor Relations Bureau (U.S.); New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations --Faculty.; United States National Labor Relations Board.
Subjects:
Arbitration, Industrial--United States--Sources.
Form and Genre Terms:
Files.; Records (documents); Papers (documents); Audiovisual materials.; Photographs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
CONTAINER LIST
- /4057: James A. Gross NLRB Files, 1933-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  15 linear feet
- /4057 AV: James A. Gross NLRB Audiocassettes, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  3.3 linear feet. Audio of James Gross's interviews with Melvin Welles, D. Pollitt, Thomas Miller, Jr., Ed Miller and Frank McCulloch.
- /4057 P: James A. Gross NLRB Photographs (Box 1, Folder 3)
  0.7 linear feet. Prof. James Gross's collection of miscellaneous NLRB photographs
- /4079: James A. Gross Additional Files (Box 1, Folder 4)
  9 linear feet
- /4124: James A. Gross Papers, Additional NLRB Research Files, 1935-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  13 linear feet
- /4166: James A. Gross Additional NLRB Research Files, 1947-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  12 linear feet
- /4166 AV: James A. Gross Additional NLRB Research Audio-Visual Materials (Box 1, Folder 7)
  13.3 linear feet. Audio recordings of Prof. Jim Gross's interviews used when he was doing research on the NLRB
- /4186: James A. Gross Additional Research Files, 1916-1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  6 linear feet
- /4190: James A. Gross Additional Research Files, 1969-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  1 linear feet
- /4232: James A. Gross Collection of NLRB 60th Annual Conference Files, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  1 linear foot
- /4351 OH: James A. Gross NLRB Oral Histories (Box 1, Folder 11)
  0.5 linear foot
- 5697: James A. Gross Arbitration Files, 1966-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  16 linear feet
- 5959: James A. Gross Additional Arbitration Files, 1978-1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)